costamar.com 2003-06-01

# Privacy policy

> Costamar.com respects your privacy, and we want you to understand the ways in which we do and don't use the information that you transmit when you visit our Web site. 
> 
> Basics  
>  The information gathered by Costamar.com falls into two categories: (1) information voluntarily supplied by visitors to our Web sites through optional registration and (2) tracking information routinely gathered as visitors navigate through our sites. 
> 
> To make use of certain features on our Web sites visitors need to register and to provide certain information as part of the registration process. (We may ask, for example, for your name, email address, gender, age and zip code.) The information you supply will help us to offer you more personalized features, to tailor our sites to your interests and to make them more useful to you. 
> 
> The more you tell us about yourself, the more value we can offer you. Supplying such information is entirely voluntary. But if you don't supply the information we need, we may be unable to provide you with services we make available to other visitors to our sites. For example, we can't offer you online travel reservations without knowing how to book your trip. And we can't send you email alerting you to any new service we're offering or breaking news that may interest you if you don't tell us your preferences and give us your email address. Similarly, we can't notify you that you've been lucky enough to win a prize in a promotional contest if we don't know how to contact you. 
> 
> Of course, even if you want to remain completely anonymous, you're still free to take advantage of the wealth of content available on our sites without registration. 
> 
> Cookies  
>  To help make our sites more responsive to the needs of our visitors, we invoke a standard feature found in browser software, called a "cookie," to assign each visitor a unique, random number, a sort of anonymous user ID that resides on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify the visitor, just the computer that a visitor uses to access our site. Unless you voluntarily identify yourself (through registration, for example), we won't know who you are, even if we assign a cookie to your computer. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply. A cookie can't read data off your hard drive. Our advertisers may also assign their own cookies to your browser, a process that we don't control. 
> 
> We use cookies to help us tailor our site to your needs, to deliver a better, more personalized service. In addition, we may use cookies to track the pages on our sites visited by our users. We can build a better site if we know which pages our users are visiting and how often. Of course, you can set your browser not to accept cookies, but if you do, you may not be able to take advantage of the personalized features enjoyed by other visitors to our sites. 
> 
> IP Addresses  
>  Our Web servers automatically collect limited information about your computer's connection to the Internet, including your IP address, when you visit our sites. (Your IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send you data - such as the Web pages you view.) Your IP address does not identify you personally. We use this information to deliver our Web pages to you upon request, to tailor our sites to the interests of our users and to measure traffic within our sites. 
> 
> Information Sharing and Sites Beyond Costamar.com  
>  To make our sites more valuable to our visitors, we may offer some features in conjunction with other providers made available through cooperative arrangements that specialize in operating such services and that will receive the information you provide when you register for, and use, these services. To take advantage of these services, you may need to provide personal information to us and to the other provider. And, of course, our sites include links to plenty of other Web sites whose privacy policies we don't control. Once you leave our servers (you can tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you're visiting. And when you provide information in the course of obtaining products or services through our site, use of any information you provide may be governed by the privacy policy of the provider of those products or services, even if it appears that you're on Discovery-branded pages throughout the transaction. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the site's homepage, you should contact the site directly for more information. 
> 
> Encryption and Security  
>  All information gathered on any Costamar.com Web site is encrypted for storage within a Costamar.com -controlled database. Costamar.com seeks to safeguard the information you provide. As effective as encryption technology is, however, no security system is completely impenetrable, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won't be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. 
> 
> Costamar Travel  
>  We are committed to safeguarding the information you submit to us when you make travel reservations and purchase travel services through Costamar Travel. We will not share any of the personally identifiable information (such as your name, address or telephone number) that you provide when you request information about a trip, make a reservation or purchase travel services through Costamar Travel, except to the related company (for example, an airline, tour operator or hotel) providing such services. 
> 
> A Final Note: The Web is an evolving medium. If we need to change our privacy policy at some point in the future, we'll post the changes here. Of course, our use of information gathered while the current policy is in effect will always be consistent with the current policy, even if we change that policy later. If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please send an email to privacypolicy@Costamar.com. Thanks for using the Costamar.com Web site!

**Costamar Travel Cruise & Tours Inc.**  
1421 E. Oakland Park Blvd.  
Fort Lauderdale, FL. 33334  
**Phone : 1-800-428-8687**
